

W: linkedin.com/in/zunaib-imtiaz/

E: zunaib60@gmail.com

P: +92 308 4225537

L: Johar Town, Lahore, Pakistan



PERSONAL INFO

Software Engineer with almost 2 plus years of **Full Stack Development** experience developing projects from diverse domains. Currently working as a Full Stack Developer in Pakistan's leading AI Organization **Afiniti** across diverse technologies. Got experience developing Fast and Responsive UIs with modular Application Servers. Love learning new things and tools every day. Driven individual with the ability to adapt to any situation and potential to grow self and others.



EDUCATION

BACHELOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING COMSATS, LAHORE

BACHELOR DEGREE | SEP 2015 - JUN 2019

INTERMEDIATE IN PRE-ENGINEERING GOVT. SCIENCE COLLEGE, LAHORE

INTERMEDIATE DEGREE | SEP 2013 - JUN 2015



EXPERIENCE

LEAD FULL STACK DEVELOPER

AFINITI – PAIR BETTER. | MAY 2019 - PRESENT

At **Afiniti** I started as an Analyst Software Engineer, initially worked on the User Interface development of an application and later on moved to Full Stack Development. I got promoted to Software Engineer in under 10 months and starting working on Full Stack Applications from scratch, training junior employees and developing services. I've worked on projects from diversified domains performing following duties,

- Developed Fast, Reliable, Responsive and Flexible UI's using ReactJS, NextJS and GatsbyJS.
- Developed User Interface for multiple devices considering specific layout, cross browser compatibility and useability.
- Developed a custom React component library for Afiniti using React, Sass and Storybook and deployed to Afiniti's NPM Proxy.
- Acquired hands on experience with 3rd party UI Libraries integration like Antd, Material UI and more UI Libraries.
- Developed Complex Dynamic Forms and used UseForm and Formik like 3rd party npm packages.
- Developed high end performance APIs using Redis, Apollo Client, GraphQL and cache managing technologies.
- Developed scalable and rigid Application Servers using NodeJS, Python and Hasura.
- Developed Middleware Services using Java and Node Js.
- Deployed Full Stack Applications using Nginx, Docker, GitHub and AWS.
- Worked on Integrating new features into Legacy Projects.
- Worked on Production Bugs and Issues.

FULL STACK FREELANCING SERVICE

UPWORK. | JUN 2020 – PRESENT

Working on **Upwork**, I've dealt with projects from diverse domains and technologies. I have encountered issues and obstacles out of an organizational environment on Upwork

which had let me to grow personally and professionally improving customer experience and my technical skills. While being a Freelancer I've performed following duties,

- Developed Client websites using React, Node, Sass, Mongo with custom clientoriented functionalities.
- Converted PSD Designs into React Pages with pixel perfect designs and accurate color schemes.
- Worked on Shopify to develop websites, integrated JavaScript and Sass into Shopify for custom features.
- Deployed Websites to custom domains using GitHub Pages, Nginx and Docker.
- Attained 100 percent Client satisfaction with my fast response and revisions.

(ii) SKILLS

- ReactJS
- NextJS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML 5/CSS 3
- SASS / Theming
- Storybook
- Photoshop

- NodeJS
- Python
- Hasura
- MongoDB
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- PhpMyAdmin

- Docker
- Nginx
- GitHub
- Bitbucket

I've worked in numerous other languages too,

- Worked on NumPy, Tensor-flow, Keras, Open-CV, Nvidia CUDA for Machine learning development.
- Worked on Back-end Technologies like GraphQL and Python Flask.
- Worked on Custom Styling with Sass, Mix-ins, Variables and Media Queries.
- Worked on building Storybook from scratch and modifying it to my needs.
- Worked for community, as I answer community questions on stack overflow too.

PROJECTS

01. CFI REVIEW

www.cfireview.com | 2020

CFIReview is a Review Website for Flying Instructors. I developed this website for an Upwork client, who wanted custom designs and a fully responsive site. This site was developed using React, Node, Mongo, Sass and Ant Design.

02. OUR FAMILY TALES

www.ourfamilytales.com | 2021

Our Family Tales is a Story Telling Website. I developed this site for an Upwork client too, she wanted a fully customizable questionnaire built into a new Shopify store, I did both to those things using some of shopify's built-in functionalities, Vanilla Java-script and Sass.

03. AIROKIT

Airokit is a React based component library I developed for Afiniti. Airokit was built using React Js, SCSS, Custom Grid System, Responsive Design, White/Dark Theme, Rollup, Storybook, Jest, Custom NPM Proxy and some third-party applications. Airokit consists of every User Interface Component required to develop a User Interface. Used Docker to deploy Storybook and deploy to Afiniti's custom proxy.

04. THE SEEK

The Seek is a Machine Learning based CCTV Surveillance System. I developed this project using React, Sass, Ant Design, Python, Python Flask, PyMongo, NumPy, Tensor-flow, Keras, Open-CV and Nvidia CUDA. This project captures CCTV Feed using Device IP's, runs an activity and an object detection model to detect suspicious activity and notify administration. The suspicious part is also recorded and stored for admin to review or use later. Demo can be provided upon request.

05. VOGUE JUNCTION

Vogue Junction is one of my own projects. The idea behind vogue junction is to combine the functionalities of an e-commerce site with the likes of YouTube, Instagram and Medium. Specially designed for Fashion Freelancers to showcase and sell their work exclusively. This site was developed using React, Node, Mongo and purely custom designed theme in Sass.

06. POINT OF SALES

Developed numerous Point of Sale Systems for Local Clients and University Projects. These POS Projects were built on different stacks with the likes of PHP, Node JS, React, Angular, MongoDB, SQL.

HONOURS & AWARDS

EXCELLENT PERFORMANCE

AFINITI

Certificate for excellent performance and commendable work during first year of my services.

EXCEPTIONAL WORK

IVY ALUMNI

Certificate of appreciation presented for exceptional work in developing next generation AI Solutions at Afiniti, a venture of Columbia and IVY Alum Zia Chishti.